$Leo~Zhang~~{\rm DPhil~Student~in~Statistics,~University~of~Oxford}$

(+44) 7749 966693 leo.zhang@stx.ox.ac.uk leozhangml.github.io

Research **INTERESTS**

My research currently focusses on the mathematical understanding of deep generative models, and their application to scientific problems. In particular, I have worked on constructing scalable algorithms, which take inspiration from ideas in geometry and category theory, for tackling biochemical problems such as de novo molecular generation.

EDUCATION

Department of Statistics, University of Oxford

Oxford, UK

DPhil in Statistical Machine Learning

2023 - (current)

- Part of the Statistics and Machine Learning (StatML) CDT.
- Advisors: Dr Rob Cornish, Dr Saifuddin Syed, Prof. Yee Whye Teh.

Department of Statistics, University of Oxford

Oxford, UK

MSc in Statistical Science, Distinction

2022 - 2023

• UK Grade: 84%, US GPA: 4.00/4.00.

Department of Mathematics, Imperial College London

London, UK

BSc in Mathematics, 1st Class

2019 - 2022

• UK Grade: 84%, US GPA: 4.00/4.00.

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. SymDiff: Equivariant Diffusion via Stochastic Symmetrisation Leo Zhang, Kianoosh Ashouritaklimi, Yee Whye Teh, Rob Cornish Arvix Preprint, 2024
- 2. Metric Flow Matching for Smooth Interpolations on the Data Manifold Kacper Kapusniak, Peter Potaptchik, Teodora Reu, Leo Zhang, Alexander Tong, Michael Bronstein, Avishek Joey Bose, Francesco Di Giovanni Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, 2024

INTERNSHIPS

Multiwave Technologies AG. | Remote

06/2021 - 09/2021

• Developed ML models for predicting signals generated by photon interactions in PET scanners.

Research **EXPERIENCE**

Durham University UROP | Durham, UK

06/2022 - 08/2022

- Developed a dimensionality reduction algorithm which identifies the equivalence relations preserving the original topology.
- Supervised by Dr Ximena Fernández and Prof. Jeffrey Giansiracusa.

Imperial College London UROP | Remote

06/2020 - 09/2020

2022

- Developed ML models for classifying videos of tennis shots.
- Supervised by Prof. William Knottenbelt.

AWARDS AND

Honors

- Dean's List, Top 10% of cohort in each year at Imperial College London. 2019 2022
- LMS UROP Bursary, Awarded by the London Mathematical Society.
- Winton Capital Prize, Best second-year group project in pure mathematics. 2021

SKILLS

Programming: Python.

Machine Learning: PyTorch, JAX.